fr en

Sébastien Coavoux

Email: contact@azoplee.com Availability: Available

Cloud Architect, Devops, Linux

About

I have 10 years experience in development and operations (Devops). I have a strong experience cloud technologies, containers, free and open source software and systems monitoring. I can architect and implement CI/CD pipelines and Kubernetes based cloud deployments. I'm familiar with Agile methodology, got a good team spirit and can communicate easily. The diversity of my missions allowed me to be more open-minded and be more autonomous. My main objective: ship work the way I would like to receive it

Experience

Azoplee.com

Senior Consultant

November 2019 - present

Client: Erudit

Assignment: Platform Migration

- · Business apps containerization with Podman
- CI/CD architecture
- · Packaging and Deployment Automation

Technical environment: Podman, Ansible, Gitlab, Openstack

Client: Bell

Assignment: Node migration in a Kubernetes cluster

- · Cluster node addition
- · Reinstall of physical nodes
- · Maintain cluster operation while migrating

Technical environment: Linux, RKE, Ansible, Helm

Assignment: Tooling and pipeline improvemnts

- · Add, update and deploy charts
- · Configuration deployment automation with ArgoCD
- Template standard configuration for new clusters

Technical environment: Gitlab, Helm, Openshift, ArgoCD, ELK, Kafka

Assignment: Support of new tenants on Openshift environments

- · Tenant onboarding
- Teach Kubernetes best ptractices
- · Business configuration setup

Technical environment: Openshift, BGP, Envoy, Helm, ArgoCD

Assignment: Public cloud strategy adoption

- · Proof of concept in various cloud provider
- · Roles and responsibility definition within internal teams
- Support strategy based on tenant expertise

Technical environment: AWS, GCP, Rosa

Customer: Axceta

Assignment: Kubernetes-based stack Audit and Helm setup

- Audit of existing architecture in Google Cloud
- Detection and fixes of design and security issues
- CI/CD pipeline improvemnt with Helm

Technical environment : Google Cloud Platform, GKE, Cloud Endpoint, Helm

Customer: Numigi

Fon (previously XCellAir)

Senior Devops Engineer

May 2017 - November 2019

Assignment: Private cloud platform

- Setup and configuration of Openstack server
- · Design of private cloud architecture
- Deployment and Configuration of Openstack with Chef
- · Contribution to Openstack Chef cookbooks to support last Openstack versions

Assignment: CI/CD pipeline

- · Migration of repositories to Gitlab Cloud and user training
- · Design and implementation of CI and CD using GitlabCI
- Team velocity improvement with a faster feedback loop
- Deployment of an internal artifacts manager (Nexus)

Assignment: Scaling plateform

- · Introduction of Docker technology in the company and user training
- · Lead containerization of business applications and technology adoption
- · Introduction of Kubernetes as next generation scaling solution
- Deployment of containerized stack in AWS and Openstack (ECS, K8s, docker compose)

Technical environment : Kubernetes, Docker, AWS, Terraform, Gitlab, Openstack, Chef, Bitbucket, Jenkins, Python, Linux

Nuance Communications

Devops Engineer

April 2016 - May 2017

Assignment: Provide a cloud based platform for other team to setup in-house app

- · Setup and configuration of a Kubernetes cluster
- Development of patch to Kubernetes to add new features
- Development of a tool to automate installation, with continuous intergration and test in cloud
- · CI pipeline and unit tests of the setup tool
- Setup, configuration, monitoring and maintenance of a docker registry for locals apps
- Proxy architecture to replicate docker images
- · Coaching of new Kubernetes users
- Integration of latest Kubernetes / Docker version to get the very last features

Technical environment : Linux, Python, Kubernetes, Docker, Azure, Go, Portus, Gitlab, DigitalOcean, Ruby

Nuance Communications

Release and Continuous Integration Engineer

November 2015 - April 2016

Assignment: Sustain CI pipeline and improve reliability

- Setup of a in-house monitoring system to detect server issues
- Use of container approach in CI to have stateless agent
- Unification of agent setup to get a homogenous infrastructure
- · Deployment automation with configuration management tool from scratch

Technical environment: Linux, Python, Salt, Docker, Bamboo, Sensu, Graphite, Grafana, Ruby

Savoir-faire Linux

Free Software Consultant

April 2013 - November 2015

Customer: Société de transport de Montréal

Assignment: Setup of a monitoring tool in a huge environnemnt

- · Setup the monitoring tool in dev env
- Development of tool generating configuration
- · Monitoring plugins development
- · Production support deployment
- · Continuous integration tests
- · Benchmarks, functional testing

Technical environment: Linux, Python, Shinken, Graphite, WMI, Talend, Ossec, Collectd, SNMP

Customer: Société de développement de la Baie-James

Assignment: Monitoring software update and hardware addition

- · Keep the software up to date with latest features
- · Monitor new hardwares, servers, softwares.
- Custimization

Technical environment: Linux, Python, Shinken, Thruk, Nagvis, Windows Server, WMI, VmWare, SNMP

Customer: Société québécoise des infrastructures

Assignment: Setup of a monitoring tool

- Setup and customization (alerting, theshold)
- · Custom development of monitoring plugins
- Formation materials

Technical environment : Linux, Python, Shinken, Centreon, MySQL, PHP, Windows Server, WMI, VmWare

Education

Polytech'Grenoble

Computer Science Engineer

Major: Networks and System

Major : Networks and Systems

2009 - 2012

Key modules: Algorithms, Systems architecture, Cryptography, Databases, Software engineering, Operating Systems, Networks, Communication, Management.

Projects

L'Atelier Candide

lateliercandide.ca

Business Process Engineering

2018 - present

Inventory operations automation

- · Product additions and updates
- · Delays detection on shippings
- · Product quantity sync between multiple website
- Detect inventory difference and protuct to order again

Technical environment: Python, Google Analytics, Shopify, GraphQL

Alignak

Main developer

2015 - 2018

Open-source monitoring framework

Major refactoring to make code compliant to Python rules

- PEP8 and Pylint compliance over the code
- · Functional and unit test additions
- Setup of development best practices (continuous integration, code review, code quality analysis)
- · Packaging automation

Technical environment: Python, Travis, Docker, Dpkg

Sébastien Coavoux - contact@azoplee.com